{"questions" : {
        "0" : {
            "question" : "",
            "A" : "",
            "B" : "",
            "C" : "",
            "right" : ""},
        "1" : {
            "question" : "Where _______ from? I’m from Russia.",
            "A" : "you are",
            "B" : "you",
            "C" : "are you",
            "right" : "are you"},
        "2" : {
            "question" : "We have ___ house in Moscow.",
            "A" : "any",
            "B" : "a",
            "C" : "an",
            "right" : "a"},
        "3" : {
            "question" : "I have two _______, a boy and a girl.",
            "A" : "sons",
            "B" : "daughters",
            "C" : "children",
            "right" : "children"},
        "4" : {
            "question" : "I work in a _______. I’m a doctor.",
            "A" : "hospital",
            "B" : "hotel",
            "C" : "supermarket",
            "right" : "hospital"},
        "5" : {
            "question" : "This is my brother. _______ name’s Paul.",
            "A" : "Her",
            "B" : "His",
            "C" : "He’s",
            "right" : "His"},
        "6" : {
            "question" : "_______ five people in my family.",
            "A" : "They are",
            "B" : "There is",
            "C" : "There are",
            "right" : "There are"},
        "7" : {
            "question" : "I get up _______ 7 o’clock in the morning.",
            "A" : "for",
            "B" : "at",
            "C" : "in",
            "right" : "at"},
        "8" : {
            "question" : "I like apples, but I _______ bananas.",
            "A" : "don’t like",
            "B" : "like",
            "C" : "do like",
            "right" : "don’t like"},
        "9" : {
            "question" : "Excuse me, _______ speak French?",
            "A" : "do you",
            "B" : "you do",
            "C" : "you",
            "right" : "do you"},
        "10" : {
            "question" : "How much are _______ shoes?",
            "A" : "this",
            "B" : "these",
            "C" : "that",
            "right" : "these"},
        "11" : {
            "question" : "Where are my glasses? They’re _______ the table.",
            "A" : "at",
            "B" : "on",
            "C" : "in",
            "right" : "on"},
        "12" : {
            "question" : "My sister _______ tennis very well.",
            "A" : "plays",
            "B" : "play",
            "C" : "playing",
            "right" : "plays"},
        "13" : {
            "question" : "I usually go to work _______ train.",
            "A" : "on",
            "B" : "with",
            "C" : "by",
            "right" : "by"},
        "14" : {
            "question" : "I don’t see my parents very often _______ they live in South Africa.",
            "A" : "so",
            "B" : "but",
            "C" : "because",
            "right" : "because"},
        "15" : {
            "question" : "Rosie stayed _______ home yesterday afternoon.",
            "A" : "in",
            "B" : "at",
            "C" : "to",
            "right" : "at"},
        "16" : {
            "question" : "Last night I _______ to the cinema.",
            "A" : "went",
            "B" : "did go",
            "C" : "was",
            "right" : "went"},
        "17" : {
            "question" : "The _______ is quite expensive but the food there is excellent.",
            "A" : "film",
            "B" : "restaurant",
            "C" : "book",
            "right" : "restaurant"},
        "18" : {
            "question" : "Do you want to listen to music or _______ TV?",
            "A" : "see",
            "B" : "look",
            "C" : "watch",
            "right" : "watch"},
        "19" : {
            "question" : "_______ were you at the weekend? I was in Scotland.",
            "A" : "When",
            "B" : "Where",
            "C" : "What",
            "right" : "Where"},
        "20" : {
            "question" : "_______ you have a good time at the party? Yes, it was fun.",
            "A" : "Did",
            "B" : "Were",
            "C" : "Had",
            "right" : "Did"},
        "21" : {
            "question" : "Are you _______ English teacher?",
            "A" : "Maria",
            "B" : "Marias’",
            "C" : "Maria’s",
            "right" : "Maria’s"},
        "22" : {
            "question" : "Bob will meet _______ at the airport.",
            "A" : "us",
            "B" : "we",
            "C" : "our",
            "right" : "us"},
        "23" : {
            "question" : "I’m going to a concert tonight. _______ you like to come?",
            "A" : "Do",
            "B" : "Are",
            "C" : "Would",
            "right" : "Would"},
        "24" : {
            "question" : "_______ use your dictionary? Sure. Here you are",
            "A" : "Could I",
            "B" : "Could you",
            "C" : "Do I",
            "right" : "Could I"},
        "25" : {
            "question" : "I like this apartment but the _______ is too expensive for me.",
            "A" : "money",
            "B" : "rent",
            "C" : "cost",
            "right" : "rent"},
        "26" : {
            "question" : "Excuse me, how do I _______ to the bus station?",
            "A" : "come",
            "B" : "get",
            "C" : "arrive",
            "right" : "get"},
        "27" : {
            "question" : "Do you sell stamps? Yes, we do. How _______ do you want?",
            "A" : "any",
            "B" : "many",
            "C" : "much",
            "right" : "many"},
        "28" : {
            "question" : "Sorry I’m so late. That’s _______.",
            "A" : "OK",
            "B" : "great",
            "C" : "right",
            "right" : "OK"},
        "29" : {
            "question" : "I’d like _______ milk in my coffee, please.",
            "A" : "some",
            "B" : "any",
            "C" : "a",
            "right" : "some"},
        "30" : {
            "question" : "_______ a bus stop near my house.",
            "A" : "It’s",
            "B" : "Here’s",
            "C" : "There’s",
            "right" : "There’s"},
        "31" : {
            "question" : "Is this a good time to talk? Sorry, no. I _______ dinner.",
            "A" : "cook",
            "B" : "am cooking",
            "C" : "cooking",
            "right" : "am cooking"},
        "32" : {
            "question" : "I think cycling is more dangerous _______ driving.",
            "A" : "as",
            "B" : "like",
            "C" : "than",
            "right" : "than"},
        "33" : {
            "question" : "We _______ going to the theatre next Saturday.",
            "A" : "will",
            "B" : "do",
            "C" : "are",
            "right" : "are"},
        "34" : {
            "question" : "_______ meet for coffee some time soon.",
            "A" : "Let’s",
            "B" : "Do you",
            "C" : "Shall they",
            "right" : "Let’s"},
        "35" : {
            "question" : "Kamal has got a holiday home near _______ sea.",
            "A" : "a",
            "B" : "the",
            "C" : "some",
            "right" : "the"},
        "36" : {
            "question" : "If you’ve got a headache, you _______ go home.",
            "A" : "should",
            "B" : "did",
            "C" : "had",
            "right" : "should"},
        "37" : {
            "question" : "_______ ever been to New York?",
            "A" : "Have you",
            "B" : "Are you",
            "C" : "Did you",
            "right" : "Have you"},
        "38" : {
            "question" : "I only get about five hours’ sleep a night. That’s not _______.",
            "A" : "enough",
            "B" : "lot",
            "C" : "too much",
            "right" : "enough"},
        "39" : {
            "question" : "Did Amina finish the report? No. She _______ it tomorrow.",
            "A" : "finishes",
            "B" : "is going to finish",
            "C" : "finished",
            "right" : "is going to finish"},
        "40" : {
            "question" : "Paula _______ loves working with children.",
            "A" : "very",
            "B" : "really",
            "C" : "much",
            "right" : "really"},
        "41" : {
            "question" : "Is Ottawa the capital of Canada? I think _______.",
            "A" : "is",
            "B" : "yes",
            "C" : "so",
            "D" : "right",
            "right" : "so"},
        "42" : {
            "question" : "We never _______ a television when I was a child.",
            "A" : "have had",
            "B" : "hadn’t",
            "C" : "had",
            "D" : "didn’t have",
            "right" : "had"},
        "43" : {
            "question" : "We paid the restaurant bill _______ credit card.",
            "A" : "to",
            "B" : "with",
            "C" : "on",
            "D" : "by",
            "right" : "by"},
        "44" : {
            "question" : "The last time I _______ Joanna was in Paris.",
            "A" : "have seen",
            "B" : "saw",
            "C" : "see",
            "D" : "was seeing",
            "right" : "saw"},
        "45" : {
            "question" : "If you _______ money from a friend, you should always pay it back promptly.",
            "A" : "borrow",
            "B" : "earn",
            "C" : "spend",
            "D" : "lend",
            "right" : "borrow"},
        "46" : {
            "question" : "Can I make myself a cup of coffee? Of course. You _______ to ask.",
            "A" : "haven’t",
            "B" : "mustn’t",
            "C" : "needn’t",
            "D" : "don’t have",
            "right" : "don’t have"},
        "47" : {
            "question" : "I _______ a lot of sport in my free time.",
            "A" : "do",
            "B" : "practise",
            "C" : "make",
            "D" : "exercise",
            "right" : "do"},
        "48" : {
            "question" : "_______ anywhere interesting recently?",
            "A" : "Do you go",
            "B" : "Have you been",
            "C" : "Are you going",
            "D" : "Will you go",
            "right" : "Have you been"},
        "49" : {
            "question" : "It’s Walter’s birthday on Friday. He _______ be 30, I think.",
            "A" : "should",
            "B" : "can",
            "C" : "will",
            "D" : "shall",
            "right" : "will"},
        "50" : {
            "question" : "Learning the piano isn’t as difficult _______ learning the violin.",
            "A" : "like",
            "B" : "so",
            "C" : "than",
            "D" : "as",
            "right" : "as"},
        "51" : {
            "question" : "If the weather _______ bad tomorrow, we can go to a museum.",
            "A" : "will be",
            "B" : "was",
            "C" : "is",
            "D" : "would be",
            "right" : "is"},
        "52" : {
            "question" : "About a billion cans of Coca-Cola _______ drunk around the world every day.",
            "A" : "is",
            "B" : "are",
            "C" : "was",
            "D" : "were",
            "right" : "are"},
        "53" : {
            "question" : "My mum’s not very well. Oh, _______.",
            "A" : "it doesn’t matter",
            "B" : "I do apologise",
            "C" : "sorry to hear that",
            "D" : "not bad, thanks",
            "right" : "sorry to hear that"},
        "54" : {
            "question" : "Hans isn’t here. He _______ to see his grandmother. He’ll be back tomorrow.",
            "A" : "has gone",
            "B" : "had been",
            "C" : "has been",
            "D" : "had gone",
            "right" : "has gone"},
        "55" : {
            "question" : "Would you mind changing my appointment? _______ time on Friday is fine.",
            "A" : "Next",
            "B" : "All the",
            "C" : "Every",
            "D" : "Any",
            "right" : "Any"},
        "56" : {
            "question" : "When I was a child, I _______ climb the wall and jump into our neighbours’ garden.",
            "A" : "would",
            "B" : "did",
            "C" : "have",
            "D" : "used",
            "right" : "would"},
        "57" : {
            "question" : "Have you finished _______ the wall yet?",
            "A" : "paint",
            "B" : "to paint",
            "C" : "painting",
            "D" : "painted",
            "right" : "painting"},
        "58" : {
            "question" : "Can you help me? I’ve tried _______ hotel in the city and can’t find a room.",
            "A" : "many",
            "B" : "any",
            "C" : "every",
            "D" : "all",
            "right" : "every"},
        "59" : {
            "question" : "Lena used to find work boring _______ she became a nurse.",
            "A" : "unless",
            "B" : "until",
            "C" : "if",
            "D" : "since",
            "right" : "until"},
        "60" : {
            "question" : "If I _______ closer to my office, I could walk to work.",
            "A" : "lived",
            "B" : "would live",
            "C" : "had lived",
            "D" : "live",
            "right" : "lived"},
        "61" : {
            "question" : "I _______ outside the cinema when suddenly a police car arrived.",
            "A" : "stood",
            "B" : "was standing",
            "C" : "have stood",
            "D" : "am standing",
            "right" : "was standing"},
        "62" : {
            "question" : "Nodody is sure where Bob is, he _______ be in his office.",
            "A" : "will",
            "B" : "may",
            "C" : "can",
            "D" : "must",
            "right" : "may"},
        "63" : {
            "question" : "We’ve _______ come back from a trip to India. It was amazing.",
            "A" : "already",
            "B" : "yet",
            "C" : "just",
            "D" : "only",
            "right" : "just"},
        "64" : {
            "question" : "I’ve got to be at work in five minutes. Don’t worry, I _______ you a lift if you want.",
            "A" : "give",
            "B" : "am giving",
            "C" : "’ll give",
            "D" : "’m going to give",
            "right" : "’ll give"},
        "65" : {
            "question" : "My doctor advised me _______ more exercise.",
            "A" : "take",
            "B" : "taking",
            "C" : "having taken",
            "D" : "to take",
            "right" : "to take"},
        "66" : {
            "question" : "I couldn’t _______ up with the noise in the city, so we moved to the countryside.",
            "A" : "put",
            "B" : "live",
            "C" : "set",
            "D" : "take",
            "right" : "put"},
        "67" : {
            "question" : "There’s no name on this dictionary. It _______ be mine then. Mine’s got my name on the front.",
            "A" : "might not",
            "B" : "mustn’t",
            "C" : "won’t",
            "D" : "can’t",
            "right" : "can’t"},
        "68" : {
            "question" : "Julia _______ married since she was 20.",
            "A" : "is",
            "B" : "was",
            "C" : "has been",
            "D" : "is being",
            "right" : "has been"},
        "69" : {
            "question" : "Don’t worry if I _______ late tonight. I’m going to the gym after work.",
            "A" : "am",
            "B" : "will be",
            "C" : "would be",
            "D" : "was",
            "right" : "am"},
        "70" : {
            "question" : "I’ve got a terrible headache, and it won’t go away. Have you tried _______ some aspirin?",
            "A" : "to take",
            "B" : "take",
            "C" : "took",
            "D" : "had taken",
            "right" : "to take"},
        "71" : {
            "question" : "Boxing is a sport _______ requires a lot of speed and fitness.",
            "A" : "it",
            "B" : "that",
            "C" : "what",
            "D" : "where",
            "right" : "that"},
        "72" : {
            "question" : "Jon _______ working on this project for a couple of months so he hasn’t made much progress yet.",
            "A" : "is only",
            "B" : "has only been",
            "C" : "was only",
            "D" : "had only been",
            "right" : "has only been"},
        "73" : {
            "question" : "I was wondering _______ I could ask you some questions. Sure, go ahead.",
            "A" : "what",
            "B" : "if",
            "C" : "that",
            "D" : "how",
            "right" : "if"},
        "74" : {
            "question" : "What clothes should I pack for a trip to Boston? Well, it depends _______ the time of year that you go.",
            "A" : "on",
            "B" : "with",
            "C" : "up",
            "D" : "to",
            "right" : "on"},
        "75" : {
            "question" : "I’ve finished this salad and I’m still hungry. I _______ ordered something more filling.",
            "A" : "must have",
            "B" : "would have",
            "C" : "should have",
            "D" : "may have",
            "right" : "should have"},
        "76" : {
            "question" : "Do you ever ask your neighbours to do favours _______ you?",
            "A" : "for",
            "B" : "to",
            "C" : "with",
            "D" : "about",
            "right" : "for"},
        "77" : {
            "question" : "Some married couples seem to get more _______ over time.",
            "A" : "alike",
            "B" : "same",
            "C" : "like",
            "D" : "equal",
            "right" : "alike"},
        "78" : {
            "question" : "I don’t know how much this card costs. The price label’s _______ off.",
            "A" : "gone",
            "B" : "taken",
            "C" : "done",
            "D" : "come",
            "right" : "come"},
        "79" : {
            "question" : "Ben got the job because he _______ a very good impression at his interview.",
            "A" : "made",
            "B" : "did",
            "C" : "put",
            "D" : "took",
            "right" : "made"},
        "80" : {
            "question" : "Salsa music always _______ me of my trip to Cuba.",
            "A" : "remembers",
            "B" : "realises",
            "C" : "recognises",
            "D" : "reminds",
            "right" : "reminds"},
        "81" : {
            "question" : "I _______ to be picking Tom up at the station but I’ve lost my keys.",
            "A" : "am supposed",
            "B" : "am requested",
            "C" : "am intended",
            "D" : "am obliged",
            "right" : "am supposed"},
        "82" : {
            "question" : "How about going to Colours nightclub? There’s no _______ I’m going there. It’s awful!",
            "A" : "hope",
            "B" : "way",
            "C" : "time",
            "D" : "opportunity",
            "right" : "way"},
        "83" : {
            "question" : "By the age of 18, I _______ not to go to university.",
            "A" : "had decided",
            "B" : "decided",
            "C" : "have decided",
            "D" : "was deciding",
            "right" : "had decided"},
        "84" : {
            "question" : "I’m afraid your car _______ repaired before next week.",
            "A" : "hasn’t been",
            "B" : "wasn’t",
            "C" : "wouldn’t be",
            "D" : "can’t be",
            "right" : "can’t be"},
        "85" : {
            "question" : "The amount of organically grown food on sale has _______ enormously in recent years.",
            "A" : "raised",
            "B" : "lifted",
            "C" : "increased",
            "D" : "built",
            "right" : "increased"},
        "86" : {
            "question" : "Can you believe it? A woman has been _______ for hacking into the computer of her online virtual husband.",
            "A" : "accused",
            "B" : "suspended",
            "C" : "arrested",
            "D" : "suspected",
            "right" : "arrested"},
        "87" : {
            "question" : "You may borrow my laptop _______ you promise to look after it.",
            "A" : "unless",
            "B" : "in case",
            "C" : "as long as",
            "D" : "although",
            "right" : "as long as"},
        "88" : {
            "question" : "It’s a huge painting. It _______ taken ages to complete.",
            "A" : "must have",
            "B" : "can’t have",
            "C" : "should have",
            "D" : "won’t have",
            "right" : "must have"},
        "89" : {
            "question" : "Pierre tends to put _______ dealing with problems, rather than dealing with them immediately.",
            "A" : "down",
            "B" : "off",
            "C" : "over",
            "D" : "away",
            "right" : "off"},
        "90" : {
            "question" : "If the taxi hadn’t stopped for us, we _______ standing in the rain.",
            "A" : "were",
            "B" : "would be",
            "C" : "are",
            "D" : "would have been",
            "right" : "would have been"},
        "91" : {
            "question" : "My mother’s Italian, so _______ the language has been quite easy for me.",
            "A" : "to learn",
            "B" : "learn",
            "C" : "having learned",
            "D" : "learning",
            "right" : "learning"},
        "92" : {
            "question" : "_______ I had the talent, I still wouldn’t want to be a movie star.",
            "A" : "In case",
            "B" : "Even if",
            "C" : "Provided that",
            "D" : "However much",
            "right" : "Even if"},
        "93" : {
            "question" : "The factory workers threatened _______ on strike if they didn’t get a pay rise.",
            "A" : "going",
            "B" : "to go",
            "C" : "that they go",
            "D" : "to have gone",
            "right" : "to go"},
        "94" : {
            "question" : "I was about to go to sleep when it _______ to me where the missing keys might be.",
            "A" : "remembered",
            "B" : "happened",
            "C" : "appeared",
            "D" : "occurred",
            "right" : "occurred"},
        "95" : {
            "question" : "There’s going to be a new department at work. They’ve asked me to _______ it up.",
            "A" : "take",
            "B" : "set",
            "C" : "put",
            "D" : "bring",
            "right" : "set"},
        "96" : {
            "question" : "If the film is a _______ success, the director will get most of the credit.",
            "A" : "big",
            "B" : "high",
            "C" : "large",
            "D" : "good",
            "right" : "big"},
        "97" : {
            "question" : "By the end of today’s seminar I will _______ to each of you individually.",
            "A" : "speak",
            "B" : "have spoken",
            "C" : "be speaking",
            "D" : "have been speaking",
            "right" : "have spoken"},
        "98" : {
            "question" : "This is a photo of my little sister _______ ice cream on the beach.",
            "A" : "eat",
            "B" : "eating",
            "C" : "was eating",
            "D" : "having eaten",
            "right" : "eating"},
        "99" : {
            "question" : "Our students take their responsibilities very _______.",
            "A" : "considerably",
            "B" : "thoroughly",
            "C" : "seriously",
            "D" : "strongly",
            "right" : "seriously"},
        "100" : {
            "question" : "Pia was _______ delighted with the birthday present.",
            "A" : "very",
            "B" : "completely",
            "C" : "fairly",
            "D" : "absolutely",
            "right" : "absolutely"},
        "101" : {
            "question" : "People were amazed that the burglary took place in _______ daylight.",
            "A" : "wide",
            "B" : "broad",
            "C" : "large",
            "D" : "open",
            "right" : "broad"},
        "102" : {
            "question" : "She invested a lot of time _______ researching the most appropriate university course.",
            "A" : "to",
            "B" : "for",
            "C" : "with",
            "D" : "in",
            "right" : "in"},
        "103" : {
            "question" : "The police claimed that they acted in self-_______.",
            "A" : "interest",
            "B" : "confidence",
            "C" : "defence",
            "D" : "discipline",
            "right" : "defence"},
        "104" : {
            "question" : "I _______ remember putting my briefcase down on that shelf.",
            "A" : "deeply",
            "B" : "entirely",
            "C" : "clearly",
            "D" : "strongly",
            "right" : "clearly"},
        "105" : {
            "question" : "He turned _______ to be considerably older than I had imagined.",
            "A" : "over",
            "B" : "up",
            "C" : "out",
            "D" : "round",
            "right" : "out"},
        "106" : {
            "question" : "The windows in this house are in urgent _______ of replacement.",
            "A" : "need",
            "B" : "help",
            "C" : "want",
            "D" : "demand",
            "right" : "need"},
        "107" : {
            "question" : "Speed cameras _______ placed to reduce accidents.",
            "A" : "have",
            "B" : "were being",
            "C" : "have been",
            "D" : "are being",
            "right" : "have been"},
        "108" : {
            "question" : "Life is a _______ deal easier for immigrants who can speak the local language.",
            "A" : "far",
            "B" : "huge",
            "C" : "big",
            "D" : "great",
            "right" : "great"},
        "109" : {
            "question" : "The experiment _______ testing people’s responses before and after drinking coffee.",
            "A" : "contained",
            "B" : "incorporated",
            "C" : "involved",
            "D" : "consisted",
            "right" : "involved"},
        "110" : {
            "question" : "We may be a bit late. We’re _______ in a traffic jam.",
            "A" : "buried",
            "B" : "stuck",
            "C" : "blocked",
            "D" : "surrounded",
            "right" : "stuck"},
        "111" : {
            "question" : "Having _______ his driving test several times, Paul finally passed at the fourth attempt.",
            "A" : "taken",
            "B" : "made",
            "C" : "had",
            "D" : "attended",
            "right" : "taken"},
        "112" : {
            "question" : "Gospel music has had a major influence _______ other musical styles, especially soul.",
            "A" : "with",
            "B" : "to",
            "C" : "about",
            "D" : "on",
            "right" : "on"},
        "113" : {
            "question" : "Maintaining an accurate balance sheet is essential, _______ business you’re in.",
            "A" : "however",
            "B" : "wherever",
            "C" : "whatever",
            "D" : "whenever",
            "right" : "whatever"},
        "114" : {
            "question" : "It’s _______ likely that this novel will win a literary prize.",
            "A" : "totally",
            "B" : "deeply",
            "C" : "strongly",
            "D" : "highly",
            "right" : "highly"},
        "115" : {
            "question" : "It’s no _______ for me to get Brad’s phone number – I’ll be seeing him tonight.",
            "A" : "point",
            "B" : "wonder",
            "C" : "secret",
            "D" : "problem",
            "right" : "problem"},
        "116" : {
            "question" : "I’d lived in Australia, so I was used to _______ on the left side of the road.",
            "A" : "driving",
            "B" : "drive",
            "C" : "having driven",
            "D" : "drove",
            "right" : "driving"},
        "117" : {
            "question" : "I don’t think the colours in Julia’s outfit _______ together.",
            "A" : "fit",
            "B" : "suit",
            "C" : "match",
            "D" : "go",
            "right" : "go"},
        "118" : {
            "question" : "Very rarely _______ here in July.",
            "A" : "it rains",
            "B" : "does it rain",
            "C" : "is it raining",
            "D" : "it is raining",
            "right" : "does it rain"},
        "119" : {
            "question" : "I prefer to buy CDs _______ download music from my computer.",
            "A" : "in contrast to",
            "B" : "as opposed to",
            "C" : "rather than",
            "D" : "in comparison to",
            "right" : "rather than"},
        "120" : {
            "question" : "The number of turtles on the island _______ by 70% over the last decade.",
            "A" : "has declined",
            "B" : "has been declining",
            "C" : "has been declined",
            "D" : "is declining",
            "right" : "has declined"}}}
